Guide to the Frank Hentschker Collection of Off and Off-Off Broadway Ephemera MSS 416
Fales Library and Special Collections
Frank Hentschker Collection of Off and Off-Off Broadway Ephemera
2004-2009
Fales Library and Special Collections
Hentschker, Frank
MSS 416
1 Linear Feet in 1 record carton.
Dr. Frank Hentschker is a faculty member in the Theatre program at The Graduate Center, City University of New York, and serves as the Executive Director and Director of Programs at the Martin E. Segal Theatre Center. The collection contains Off and Off-Off Broadway ephemera Hentschker collected, including fliers, invitations, and programs. Materials date from 2004 to 2009.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Frank Hentschker in 2006. The accession number associated with this gift is 2014.416.
Arrangement
Materials are arranged alphabetically by name of venue.
Biographical Note
Dr. Frank Hentschker holds a Ph.D. in Theatre from the Theatre Institute in Giessen, Germany and joined the Faculty of the Ph.D. Program in Theatre at The Graduate Center, City University of New York, in 2009. Frank Hentschker is the Executive Director and Director of Programs at the Martin E. Segal Theatre Center at the CUNY Graduate Center. Through his work at the Segal Theatre Center, Hentschker founded the annual festival Prelude: At the Forefront of Contemporary NYC Theatre and PEN: World Voices Playwrights Series. Before working at CUNY, Hentschker worked as a producer, consultant, and actor, in the U.S. and Europe.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains Off and Off-Off Broadway ephemera collected by Frank Hentschker. Materials include fliers, invitations, and programs. The materials date from 2004 to 2009.
Off-Broadway theater.; Off Off-Broadway theater.; Theater -- New York (State); Hentschker, Frank
- 59 E 59 Theaters, 2006-2008 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Abingdon Theatre Arts Complex, 2006-2009 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Abrons Arts Center, 2006-2008 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Academy of American Poets, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- The Ailey Citigroup Theater, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- The Algonquin Hotel, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- American Tap Dance Foundation, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Anthology Film Archives, 2006-2008 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Asia Society, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- The Barrow Group, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Barry S. Brook Center for Music Research and Documentation, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Baruch Performing Arts Center, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Baryshnikov Arts Center, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- The Beckett Theatre, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Bond Street Theatre, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Boomerang Theatre Company, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- The Brecht Forum, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- BRICstudio, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Brooklyn Academy of Music, 2006-2008 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Brooklyn Public Library, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Carnegie Hall, 2006-2009 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Cave, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Cedar Lake Contemporary Ballet, 2007-2008 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Center for Architecture Foundation, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Center State NY, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Center Theatre Group, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Chelsea Piers - Pier 61, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Chelsea Studios, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- The Chocolate Factory, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Christopher Caines Dance Company, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Church Street School for Music and Art, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
- City of New York Parks and Recreation, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- The Civilians, 2008-2009 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Clark Studio Theatre, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Classic Stage Company, 2007-2008 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Collective:Unconscious, 2007-2008 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Columbia University Law School, undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Consulate General of Spain in New York Cultural Department, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Czech Center of New York, 2007-2008 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Dance New Amsterdam, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Dance Theater Workshop, 2008-2009 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Danspace Project at St. Mark's Church-in-the-Bowery, 2006-2008 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Dicapo Opera Theatre, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Dimson Theatre, undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Double Edge Theatre, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Douglas Dunn and Dancers, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- The Duke on 42nd Street, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- DUO Theatre, undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Earthdance, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- East 13th Street Theatre, undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Elebash Recital Hall, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Encompass New Opera Theatre, 2006-2008 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Ensemble for the Romantic Century, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Epic Theatre Center, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Eugene Lang College, undated (Box 1, Folder 55)
- The Field, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- The Flea Theatre, undated (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Florence Gould Hall, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 58)
- French Institute, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 59)
- free103point9, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 60)
- Galapagos Arts Space, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 61)
- Goethe-Institut, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 62)
- Gotham Chamber Opera, 2007-2008 (Box 1, Folder 63)
- The Graduate Center of the City University of New York, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 64)
- Guerilla Girls on Tour, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 65)
- Harlem Stage, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 66)
- Here Arts Center, 2007-2008 (Box 1, Folder 67)
- Highline Ballroom, undated (Box 1, Folder 68)
- Hudson Guild Theatre, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 69)
- Hundred Grand, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 70)
- Institute of Contemporary Art Boston, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 71)
- Instituto Cervantes, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 72)
- Istituto Italiano di Cultura, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 73)
- Japan Society, 2007-2009 (Box 1, Folder 74)
- Jewish Community Center in Manhattan, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 75)
- The Joyce Theater, 2006-2008 (Box 1, Folder 76)
- The Kennedy Center, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 77)
- Kentucky Center, undated (Box 1, Folder 78)
- The Kitchen, 2006-2008 (Box 1, Folder 79)
- La MaMa, 2006-2008 (Box 1, Folder 80)
- Lafayette Street Theatre, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 81)
- LaGuardia Performing Arts Center, 2007-2008 (Box 1, Folder 82)
- Leo Kesting Gallery, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 83)
- Lincoln Center, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 84)
- The Living Theatre, 2007-2008 (Box 1, Folder 85)
- Location One, 2006-2008 (Box 1, Folder 86)
- Long Island University, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 87)
- Ma-Yi Theater Company, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 88)
- Manhattan Children's Theatre, undated (Box 1, Folder 89)
- Manhattan Class Company, 2008-2009 (Box 1, Folder 90)
- Manhattan Plaza, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 91)
- Manhattan Theatre Club, 2008-2009 (Box 1, Folder 92)
- MAPP International, 2008-2009 (Box 1, Folder 93)
- Martin Segal Theatre Center, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 94)
- Martin Segal Theatre Center, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 95)
- Massachusetts International Festival of the Arts, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 96)
- Metropolitan Playhouse, 2007-2008 (Box 1, Folder 97)
- Mint Theater, undated (Box 1, Folder 98)
- Montclair State University, 2006-2009 (Box 1, Folder 99)
- Mulberry Street Theater, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 100)
- MultiArts Projects and Productions, 2007-2008 (Box 1, Folder 101)
- The Museum of Modern Art, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 102)
- New Dance Alliance, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 103)
- New Dance Group, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 104)
- New Dramatists, 2007-2008 (Box 1, Folder 105)
- New Georges, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 106)
- The New Group, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 107)
- New Jersey Repertory Company, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 108)
- New Victory Theater, 2008-2009 (Box 1, Folder 109)
- New York City Center, 2007-2008 (Box 1, Folder 110)
- New York City Opera, undated (Box 1, Folder 111)
- New York Library for the Performing Arts, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 112)
- New York Theatre Workshop, 2007-2009 (Box 1, Folder 113)
- New World Stages, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 114)
- The Ohio Theatre, 2007-2008 (Box 1, Folder 115)
- Ontological Theater, undated (Box 1, Folder 116)
- Pan Asian Repertory Theatre, 2007-2009 (Box 1, Folder 117)
- Pearl Theatre Company, 2006-2009 (Box 1, Folder 118)
- Performance Space 122, 2006-2008 (Box 1, Folder 119)
- The Players Loft, undated (Box 1, Folder 120)
- The Players Theatre, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 121)
- Playhouse Sqaure Center, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 122)
- Playwrights Horizons, 2007-2009 (Box 1, Folder 123)
- Polish Cultural Institute, 2008-2009 (Box 1, Folder 124)
- Portland Institute for Contemporary Art, 2006-2008 (Box 1, Folder 125)
- Presbyterian Church of Saint Albans, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 126)
- Primary Stages, undated (Box 1, Folder 127)
- Professional Staff Congress Union Hall at CUNY, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 128)
- Prospect Theater Company, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 129)
- The Public Theater, 2006-2009 (Box 1, Folder 130)
- The Puffin Room, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 131)
- Purple Man Theater Company, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 132)
- Queens Theatre in the Park, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 133)
- Red Bull Theater, undated (Box 1, Folder 134)
- REDCAT, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 135)
- River to River Festival, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 136)
- Romanian Cultural Institute, 2006-2008 (Box 1, Folder 137)
- Roundabout Theatre Company, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 138)
- St. Ann's Warehouse, 2006-2009 (Box 1, Folder 139)
- Saint Peter's Church, undated (Box 1, Folder 140)
- Shelter Studios and Theatre, undated (Box 1, Folder 141)
- The Shop, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 142)
- Skewed Visions, undated (Box 1, Folder 143)
- Skirball Center, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 144)
- SoHo Playhouse, undated (Box 1, Folder 145)
- Soho Rep, 2008-2009 (Box 1, Folder 146)
- Spiegeltent, undated (Box 1, Folder 147)
- Sponsored by Nobody, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 148)
- State Theatre New Jersey, 2008-2009 (Box 1, Folder 149)
- Steps on Broadway, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 150)
- Target Margin Theater, 2006-2008 (Box 1, Folder 151)
- Teatro IATI, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 152)
- Teatro Stage Fest, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 153)
- Theater Bielefeld, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 154)
- Theater Breaking Through Barriers, 2008-2009 (Box 1, Folder 155)
- Theater der Jugend am Elizabethplatz, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 156)
- Theater for the New City, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 157)
- Theater Mitu, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 158)
- Theater Three, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 159)
- Theatre 80, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 160)
- Theatre for a New Audience, 2007-2008 (Box 1, Folder 161)
- Theatre Project Baltimore, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 162)
- Theatres at 45 Bleecker, undated (Box 1, Folder 163)
- Tisch School of the Arts, undated (Box 1, Folder 164)
- The Town Hall, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 165)
- The Tree Studio, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 166)
- Union Street Dance, undated (Box 1, Folder 167)
- University Settlement, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 168)
- Unterberg Poetry Center, 2008-2009 (Box 1, Folder 169)
- Untitled Theater Company #61, 2006-2008 (Box 1, Folder 170)
- Vassar College, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 171)
- Vital Theatre, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 172)
- Walt Whitman Theatre at Brooklyn College, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 173)
- West End Theatre, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 174)
- Wings Theatre, undated (Box 1, Folder 175)
- Workshop Theater, undated (Box 1, Folder 176)
- The Xoregos Performing Company, undated (Box 1, Folder 177)
- The Yale Cabaret, 2008-2009 (Box 1, Folder 178)
- York College, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 179)
- The Zipper Factory Underground, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 180)